So we're now going to start week one of the course when we are going to be looking at exploring frontier
강의 첫 주에는 개척자 모델을 살펴볼 겁니다 첫날에 무엇이 가능한지
models, models at the forefront of what's possible in this first day, we're going to set up an environment
최전선에서 살펴볼 겁니다 환경을 설정하고 첫 LM 솔루션을
and then build your first LM solution.
구축할 거예요
We're then going to talk about how to be positioned for success in the next few weeks.
앞으로 몇 주 동안 어떻게 하면 성공할 수 있을지 얘기해 보죠
We're then going to compare models at the very frontier of what's possible.
그리고 최첨단 모델을 비교해 볼 거예요
Some that you know well and some I think will be new to you.
당신이 잘 아는 것도 있고 처음 보는 것도 있어요
We're then going to talk about transformers, which is the architecture at the heart of the different
다음은 트랜스포머에 관해 이야기할 거예요 이번 수업에서 다룰
models that we use in this course, almost all of the models.
거의 모든 모델의 핵심 구조물이죠
And then finally, we'll end with a juicy commercial project that you'll be able to use, and I'll have
마지막으로 여러분이 사용할 수 있는 상업 프로젝트로 마무리할 거예요 여러분 것으로 만들
an exercise for you to make it your own.
수 있는 연습 과제를 드릴게요
Apply it to different business areas, something that maybe you can use in your day job immediately.
다양한 비즈니스 영역에 적용하세요 본업에서 바로 사용할 수 있는 거죠
Maybe you'll be able to use it as a project that you can have as an example project for yourself.
프로젝트로 사용할 수도 있고 예제로 가질 수도 있어요
So we're now going to get hopefully some satisfying instant results for you.
이제 만족스러운 즉석 결과를 얻게 될 거예요 get it
We already used a llama to do some some fun things on your computer already, but now we're going to
라마는 이미 여러분 컴퓨터에서 재미있는 걸 했었죠 이번엔
take it a notch higher by calling out to APIs directly.
한 단계 더 높일 겁니다 API를 직접 호출해서요
But first, the necessary first step is to set up your environment, create a full spec data science
하지만 먼저 필요한 건 여러분의 환경을 설정하는 겁니다 앞으로 진행할 8주 프로그램을 모두 통과할
environment that will have the the sufficient horsepower to take you through the entire eight week program
수 있을 만큼 충분한 마력을 갖춘 데이터 과학 환경을 만드는 거죠
And there's quite a lot of stuff that we're going to need to install to make sure we're at that point.
그 지점에 도달하기 위해 설치해야 할 게 꽤 많아요
And I guess I should mention that sometimes, sometimes this experience can be a bit frustrating.
이 말을 해야겠네요 비트 박스를 하다 보면 가끔 답답할 때가 있어요
Most of the time it goes really smoothly and everything just fits in place.
대부분은 아주 매끄럽게 진행되고 모든 게 제자리에 들어맞아요
And it's five minutes and you're done.
5분이면 다 익어요
But sometimes some people hit speed bumps for whatever reason, because of something about the system
하지만 어떤 사람들은 어떤 이유에서든 과속 방지 턱에 부딪히죠
or or some other new effect.
시스템 문제나 새로운 효과 때문에요
And it can be a bit frustrating, but I am here to take you through it step by step and make sure it's
힘들 수도 있지만 제가 차근차근 설명해 드릴게요 성공적으로 진행되도록요
successful for you so that this will go smoothly.
그래야 비트가 순조롭죠
It'll be behind you in no time, and we'll be on to actual projects, and we'll never have to worry
곧 뒤로 물러날 겁니다 실제 프로젝트로 넘어가 앞으로 8주간은
about environment setup again for the next eight weeks.
환경 설정 걱정을 안 해도 돼요
So creating the full spec data science environment, it ain't as easy as I wish it were.
전체 스펙 데이터 과학 환경을 만드는 건 생각만큼 쉽지 않아요
There is some stuff to do, but we'll get through it fast.
할 일이 좀 있지만 빨리 끝낼 거예요 get it get it
First of all, we'll clone the repo for people who are familiar with git.
먼저, 깃을 잘 아는 사람들을 위해 압류 차량을 복제할 거예요
That's a that's easy, but but I will make sure I walk you through it in case this is a new thing.
그건 쉽죠 하지만 제가 꼭 알려드릴게요 이게 새로운 것일 수 있으니까요
Then we will go through the Readme instructions to set up the environment.
그런 다음 읽기 설명서를 통해 환경을 설정하죠
Now I recommend that we use something called Anaconda that some of you may have already used Anaconda.
아나콘다라는 걸 사용하길 권해드립니다 이미 사용해본 분들도 계실 거예요
It's a high powered thing and it's quite heavyweight.
힘이 세고 꽤 묵직해요
It creates an entire environment for you, a dedicated, isolated environment on your computer for this
이 과정을 위해 여러분 컴퓨터에 전용적이고 격리된 환경을 만들어줍니다
course, and it does so in a way that guarantees high compatibility between what you're doing on your
여러분이 하는 것과 제가 하는 것, 그리고 다른 모든 과정 사이에 높은
computer and what I do on mine and everyone else on this course.
호환성을 보장하는 거죠
So it's very good at that.
아주 잘하죠
But it is quite heavyweight.
하지만 꽤 묵직해요
It involves downloading a lot from the internet and installs a lot because it builds everything from
인터넷에서 많이 다운로드 받고 설치도 많이 해야 해요 모든 걸 처음부터
the ground up.
만들거든요
If it causes you problems, there's an alternative.
그게 문제가 된다면 대안이 있어요
We can use a simpler approach.
더 간단한 방법을 쓸 수도 있어요
The standard Python virtual environment approach with Pip, and I've got instructions for that too.
Pip의 표준 파이썬 가상 환경 접근 방법에 대한 설명도 가지고 있어요
It's quicker, it's simpler, and it's just not as guaranteed to be compatible as Anaconda, so I'd
더 빠르고 단순하고 아나콘다만큼 호환이 확실하지 않아요 가능하면 아나콘다를
prefer we try Anaconda if possible.
시도해 보려고요
It does work most of the time.
대체로 잘 작동해요
Any problems at all?
아무 문제 없었어요?
The Python virtual environment is your fallback.
파이썬 가상 환경은 대체책이죠
We then need to set up an OpenAI key and I'll talk more about that.
OpenAI 키를 설정해야 하는데 나중에 더 얘기할게요
I'll talk about API costs and what to do if that's a that's a problem for you.
API 비용에 대해 얘기할게요 그게 여러분께 문제가 될 경우 어떻게 해야 할지요
We'll go through that at the time.
그때 가서 얘기하죠
We have to create something called a EMV file, which has your private keys in it.
EMV 파일이라는 걸 만들어야 해요 개인 키가 들어 있는 거죠
And it's going to be important that that file is called exactly dot EMV, as we'll see.
파일이 정확히 .MV로 불려야 한다는 게 중요해요
I will explain, but it can't be called keys dot EMV or dot EMV dot text.
설명할게요, 하지만 키즈. EMV. EMV.Txt는 안 돼요
It has to be called exactly dot EMV.
정확히 .MV라고 불러야 해요
And then finally we activate your environment and we run JupyterLab to start the program.
마지막으로 환경을 활성화하고 주피터랩을 실행해 프로그램을 시작해요
So as I say, most of the time all of this will go great.
말씀드렸듯이 대부분은 다 잘 될 거예요
Most people report that everything goes through fine, but if it doesn't, then then there are some
대부분은 모든 게 잘 진행된다고 보고하지만 그렇지 않다면 마음대로
secret weapons at your disposal to make sure that it does.
쓸 수 있는 비밀 병기가 있죠
The first of them is that I've put a troubleshooting notebook that I will show you in, in the in,
그 중 첫 번째는 문제 해결 공책입니다 깃허브 리포에 있는 걸 보여드릴게요
in the GitHub repo, which will take you step by step through diagnosing problems, running some code
문제를 단계별로 진단하고 뭐가 잘못됐는지 코드를
that will figure out what's wrong, and then fixing each problem in turn.
실행해 하나씩 고쳐요
So that is there.
저기 있네요
The second resource you have is a kind of surprising one at ChatGPT and and Claude.
두 번째 자원은 챗GPT와 클로드에 있는 놀라운 자원이에요
They are spooky in how good they are.
얼마나 잘하는지 소름 끼쳐요
If you say a problem and paste like a stack trace in there, they are very, uh, impressive at giving
문제를 말하고 스택 트레이스처럼 붙여넣기를 하면 아주 인상적이에요 해야 할 일에 대해
quite nuanced answers about what you need to do.
아주 미묘한 답을 주거든요
I've been caught off guard by the times I've run into an infrastructure problem, and I thought, this
인프라 문제와 마주칠 때마다 허를 찔린 적이 있는데 이건 너무 심하다고
is way too much.
생각했어요
I can't even get the answer on Stack Overflow.
Get up OVERflow 스택도 못 맞히겠어요
Uh, but I've been rescued by Claude.
클로드가 절 구해줬어요
I think Claude is the stronger of the two.
클로드가 더 강한 것 같아요
But.
하지만요
But both of them give good answers.
하지만 둘 다 좋은 답을 내놓았죠
So it's worth realizing that you can often just fix the problem by pasting it in there.
그러니 가끔은 그냥 붙여서 문제를 해결할 수 있다는 걸 아셔야 해요
It's worth giving it a shot.
시도해 볼 만해요
But if if if those two fail, or even if you'd just rather go straight to this third option.
하지만 그 두 가지가 실패하거나 아니면 바로 이 세 번째 선택지를 선택해도 돼요
The third option is there, and the third option is to contact me.
세 번째 방법은 저한테 연락하는 거예요
I am standing by to help you.
당신을 도우려고 대기 중이에요
That is my job.
그게 제 일이에요
So please, please reach out.
그러니 제발 연락 좀 주세요
You can reach out to me by messaging me on the platform.
저한테 연락하실 거면 플랫폼에서 메시지로 하세요
You can email me.
이메일로 보내주세요
My email address is in the is in the readme and you can also linked in with me.
제 이메일 주소는 읽기 안에 있어요 저와 링크할 수도 있고요
I love getting LinkedIn connections by the way.
그나저나 전 링크트인 연결망이 좋아요
So LinkedIn with me for sure and message me there too and you'll find that I'm very responsive.
LinkedIn도 물론 있고요 거기도 메시지를 보내주세요 제가 아주 반응하는 걸 보실 수 있어요
I typically if I'm not sleeping or traveling, then you'll see from my other answers that I get back
잠을 자지 않거나 여행을 가지 않으면 다른 답변을 보면 금방 답이 와요
very quickly, and I see it as my job to fix it and to get you up and running.
그걸 고치고 get up 작동시키는 게 제 일이라고 생각하죠
And I have never failed.
난 실패한 적이 없어요
Yet I have always, I think, 5000 people through and everyone has a running environment, as will you.
하지만 5천 명이 모두 작업 환경을 갖추고 있어요
So if you do hit any speed bumps at all, you can go with these other two options.
과속 방지턱에 부딪히면 이 두 가지 옵션을 선택하세요
But you can come straight to me.
나한테 바로 와도 돼요
I will fix it.
제가 해결할게요
I will find what's going on.
무슨 일인지 알아볼게요
We will have you up and running quickly.
금방 다시 시작할 수 있어요
All right.
좋아요
With that, let me now take you on a walkthrough of what it takes to set up your environment.
이제 여러분 환경을 설정하는 데 필요한 걸 보여드리죠